Amira Khalfan Al 'Asmi

Al-Shabia, Adam, Al Dakhlya Sultanate of Oman Mobile No: 93337814

email: amira.alasmi@gmail.com

Instructor
Department of Engineering
Nizwa College of Technology, Nizwa

email: amira.alasmi@nct.edu.om

Career Objective

Keenly interested in pursuing a responsible and challenging position in the Information Technology Industry, in particular in a company which believes in excellence through teamwork where my experience of over 10 years, creative initiative, ideas and a genuine enthusiasm would allow me to progress.

Core Skills and Abilities

- **♣ Skills:** C, python, C++, HTML, JAVA, MySQL
- **Tools:** Microsoft Office: Word, Excel and PowerPoint, Adobe, Photoshop, Matlab, Wireshark Software, Network monitoring software, Packet tracer program
- Expertise in current and emerging trends and techniques
- Cohesive team worker, having strong analytical, problem solving skills.
- **Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills with the ability to negotiate effectively with both internal and external stakeholders at all levels.**
- **Extensive working Knowledge with switches, routers, firewall system UPS and servers**
- Initiator in implementing the health and safety procedures are followed in laboratories and Workshops.
- Installed software, modified and repaired hardware and resolved technical issues.
- Proficiency in analysing the operations and features of the network layer protocols and services and knowledge about the fundamental concept of routing
- Knowledge about the use of Cisco CLI commands to preform basic router and switch configuration.

Personal Strengths

- A team player with excellent communications and interpersonal skills
- Willingness to learn, team facilitator and hard worker
- Very much interested in programming
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills
- Goal oriented: results achiever, Meeting deadlines
- Analytical and Problem Solving Skills
- Positive Attitude: Creating a positive work environment
- Delegating tasks in stipulated time, while maintaining work balance.
- Native speaker in Arabic with excellent command in speaking and writing English.

Education

Course Completed	Institution	% of marks/ GPA	Year
BE in Computer and Communication Engineering,	Dublin Institute of Technology, Kevin Street, Dublin 8	Second class Honours	2013-2015
BEng.Tech in Eng Laboratory Technology	Dublin Institute of Technology, Kevin Street, Dublin 8		2008-2010
Higher Diploma in Computer Engineering,	Nizwa College of Technology, Nizwa, Oman	3.23	2005-2008
Foundation Program	Nizwa College of Technology, Nizwa, Oman	Intermediate level (B), Advanced level (B-) Mathematics (90%).	2004-2005
General Education	Safaya A'm Almuminin School, Adam, Oman	81.51%	2003-2004

Certification(s) / Awards

- Excellence award from Nizwa College of Technology in the Academic Year 2018-2019.
- Certification course in CCNA Exploration: Network Fundamentals in 2010.
- Certification course in IC³ in 2011.
- Certificate Training Program in Personal Strategic Planning, Adam, Oman 28-29 June 2011.
- Training Program in Information Technology, OmanTel, Nizwa Unit, March- May 2014.
- Training in Directorate General of education, Nizwa, Oman, May August 2014.
- English Foundation Course, Kenilworth Institute, c/o Kenilworth Square, Rathgar, Dublin 6 in 2008.
- English Foundation Course, Higher College of Technology, Muscat, Oman.

Work Experience:

Nizwa College of Technology (Ministry of Manpower)

Designation: Instructor (Sept 2010- Till Date)

Courses Taught: C programming, Python, Computer Networking

Responsibilities:

- Teaching and carrying out the practical training for the set syllabi and keeping its records.
- Key Personnel in setting up practical examinations for different courses handled.

- In charge for scheduling the equipment maintenance.
- Supervising the students' on-the-job training.
- Participating in the practical training activities.
- Keeping a record of student results, activities and attendance.
- Ensuring the health and safety procedures to be followed in laboratories and workshops.
- Assisting in preparing and conducting examinations and preparing student counselling forms.
- Getting acquainted with techniques of delivering lectures and lessons.
- Offering assistance to low achievers.
- Carrying out any other tasks assigned by the concerned heads of centre, department, or section.

Designation: Computer Lab Technician (June 2010 – Aug 2013)

Labs in Charge: Operating Systems, UNIX and LINUX, Computer Architecture, Data Structure.

Responsibilities:

- Effectively prioritized and executed time in high pressure environments.
- Organizing laboratories and workshops in coordination with the heads, or any teaching staff.
- Review, configure, update and implement software to safeguard critical systems, information and data.
- Create and maintain high-quality documentation of all relevant specifications, systems, and procedures.
- Keeping and updating inventory records of all the materials and equipment in the laboratories and workshops, in addition to implementing the equipment maintenance schedule.
- Cooperating with teaching and technical staff in preparing and delivering course materials.
- Receiving materials from suppliers, making sure of their compliance with the specifications, and making entries.
- Ensuring that health and safety procedures are followed in laboratories and workshops.
- Carrying out any other tasks assigned by the head of centre, department, or section.

Designation: Department Coordinator, Department of Engineering (June 2010 – Aug 2013)

Responsibilities:

- Analyze and coordinate daily department activities to achieve established goals.
- Maintain department calendar and ensure to meet deadlines.
- Prepare meeting agenda, schedule department meetings and distribute minutes.
- Coordinate and organize department related special events.
- Maintain all department information confidential and secure.
- Respond to work requests from department staffs in timely and accurate manner.
- Coordinate with faculty and maintain faculty database.
- Provide support and guidance to academic trainees.

- Collaborate with faculty to conduct workshops and seminars.
- ➤ Work with parents and teachers to address students' behavioural, academic, and other problems.
- Provide general administrative and clerical support.
- Perform data collection, analysis and reporting to Head of Department for decision making purposes.
- ➤ Draft letters, correspondence, memos, charts, documents, tables, graphs, and plans as requested.
- Maintain positive working relationships with department staffs and customers.
- Perform ad-hoc duties as assigned by the Head of the Department.

Courses and Training Completed:

Certification in CCNA Exploration: Network Fundamentals (February 2010)

School of Electronic and Communication Engineering, Dublin Institute of Technology, Kevin Street, Dublin 8.

Training Underwent:

- Understand how communication works in data networks and in the internet.
- To recognize the devices and services that are used to support communication across an internetwork.
- To explain the role of protocols in data network.
- Describe the importance of addressing and naming sachems at various layers of data networks.
- Describe the protocols and services provided by the application layer in the OSI model and describe how this layer operates in sample networks.
- Analyze the operations and feature of the transport layer protocols and services.
- Analyze the operations and features of the network layer protocols and services and explain the fundamental concept of routing.
- Design, calculate and apply subnet masks.
- Describe the operation of protocols at the data link layer.
- Explain the role of physical layer protocols and services.
- Build sample Ethernet network using routers and switches.
- Use Cisco CLI commands to preform basic router and switch configuration.

Course in IC³, Nizwa, Oman (June 2011)

Training Underwent:

Less Extensive training on Computing fundamentals, Key application and Living online.

Training in Directorate General of education, Nizwa, Oman (May - August 2014):

Training Underwent:

- ❖ Trained in wired and wireless networks.
- Identified the component and concept of wire and wireless network.
- ❖ Identify the operating system of hardware in the server room.
- ❖ Trained in windows 8 server installation & the setting of domain, DHCP & DNS.
- ❖ Worked with switches, routers, firewall system UPS and servers.

Worked with antiviruses programs.

On Job Training (OJT), Higher College of Technology, Muscat, Oman (Feb 2010 – May 2010)

Training Underwent:

- ❖ To maintain the hardware of the computer.
- ❖ Hands on training on Software and Hardware installation.
- ❖ In depth knowledge on basic programs like (Microsoft Office: Word, Excel and PowerPoint).
- ❖ Familiarization of packet tracer program, DOS and Linux, Make projects, Photoshop and C programming.
- ❖ Basic training on Matlab, PSpice, Network Monitoring Software, Wireshark software.

Positions Held:

- Coordinator, Alumni Committee, Nizwa College of Technology during 2016 till date.
- ♣ Member, Social Committee, Nizwa College of Technology, during 2018-till date.
- Translator, Arabic English and English Arabic for official documents in the Department.
- ♣ Department Coordinator, Department of Engineering, Nizwa College of Technology during 2010- 2013.

Hobbies /Interests

- ✓ Driving: Full, Clean driving License.
- ✓ Member of NCT Health Club, spreading awareness in the society to provide a healthy environment.
- ✓ Travel, Camping Trips, Cooking, Reading, Interior Design, Photography, Card Games and Computer Games, Shopping.

References

Available on Request